Guide to the Rachel Marshall Goetz Papers 1898-1994
University of Chicago Library
Goetz, Rachel Marshall. Papers
1898-1994
13.75 linear feet (23 boxes)
Hanna Holborn Gray Special Collections Research Center University of Chicago Library 1100 East 57th Street Chicago, Illinois 60637 U.S.A.
Rachel Marshall Goetz was a writer, researcher, and activist who spent much of her career focused on national and local Hyde Park politics. These papers include much of Goetz’s early writing advocating the use of new media in state and local governments. She worked as a speechwriter on Illinois governor Adlai Stevenson’s 1956 presidential campaign, and many of her drafts, memos, position papers, and letters are included here. Throughout the 1950s and 1960s, Goetz was an important figure in Hyde Park-Kenwood’s urban renewal, and her papers hold many drafts, clippings, and notes relating to that project. Late in her life, Goetz and her sister, Barbara Frye, dedicated themselves to making elaborately decorated ornamental eggs. Many photographs, articles, and letters about her egg artwork are included here. The collection also holds clippings, correspondence, and photographs relating to Goetz’s father, Leon Carroll Marshall.
Information on Use
Access
Series V contains reel-to-reel and cassette tapes which require audio equipment for access.
The remainder of the collection is unrestricted and open for research.
Biographical Note
Rachel Marshall Goetz was born in 1904 in Delaware, Ohio. The daughter of University of Chicago Business School founder and dean, Leon Carroll Marshall, she attended the University’s Laboratory School, the College and the Graduate School of Business, earning a master’s degree in business in 1927. She lived in Hyde Park for 65 years and maintained close ties to the community throughout her life.
Early in her career, Goetz worked with her friend Ursula Batchelder Stone, the first woman to be granted a Ph. D. in business at the University of Chicago. They formed the Batchelder and Marshall Research Organization, authoring several studies including "Chicago’s Stake in International Trade." She also worked closely with the Illinois League of Women Voters.
In 1949, after the death of her husband, Roger Goetz, she undertook significant work on the use of new media by state and local governments. Rachel Goetz wrote several pamphlets and articles on the use of visual aids in public service and developed a course on educational television, which she taught at the University of Chicago during the 1954-1955 academic year. Goetz also won the competition to name Chicago’s public television station’s call letters with her entry, "WTTW, Chicago’s Window to the World."
In 1955, Goetz joined the presidential campaign staff of Illinois governor Adlai Stevenson. She worked as a speechwriter, helping to craft Stevenson’s statements on a variety of issues, with special focus on the female vote. She maintained a close relationship with Stevenson through the late 1950s and early 1960s.
Throughout the 1950s and 1960s, Goetz focused considerable time and energy on the Hyde Park-Kenwood urban renewal project. She was a founding member of the Hyde Park-Kenwood Community Conference, and she sat on the board of the South East Chicago Commission. Goetz was influential in the establishment of the Hyde Park Co-op grocery store, and she helped in the planning of the Kenwood Shopping Center on 53rd street.
In 1972, Goetz moved to Alexandria, Virginia and focused her energy on creating ornamental eggs, a decorative art form exemplified by the work of Carl Peter Fabergé. Her work has been widely praised within the egg artist community, and has been displayed at the Smithsonian Institution, Mount Vernon, the Illinois state capitol, the University of Chicago Graduate School of Business.
Goetz funded a fellowship in her father’s name at the Graduate School of Business. Later, this fellowship’s funding enabled the establishment of the Leon Carroll Marshall and Mary Keen Marshall Scholarship and the Roger L. and Rachel M. Goetz Professorship in Creative Management. Goetz died on November 15, 1994
Scope Note
The Rachel Marshall Goetz Papers consist of six series. Series I contains Goetz’s early work on new media and their potential uses in government. Series II holds papers relating to her work in Adlai Stevenson’s 1956 presidential campaign staff and her later writing on national politics. Series III consists of writing and research on local Hyde Park politics and the Hyde Park-Kenwood Urban Renewal Project. Series IV contains personal writings, clippings, and photographs, including items related to Goetz’s egg art and material about her father, Leon C. Marshall. Series V holds audio resources including reel-to-reel tapes and cassette tapes. Series VI contains the collection’s oversized materials, such as posters and photographs.
Related Resources
The following related resources are located in the Department of Special Collections:
http://www.lib.uchicago.edu/e/spcl/select.html
Hyde Park-Kenwood Community Conference. Records
Marshall, Leon C. Papers
Merriam, Robert E. Papers
South East Chicago Commission. Records
Stone, Ursula Batchelder. Papers
Subject Headings
Goetz, Rachel Marshall; Marshall, Leon C. (Leon Carroll), b. 1879; Merriam, Robert Edward, 1918; Stevenson, Adlai E. (Adlai Ewing), 1900-1965; Stone, Ursula Batchelder; League of Women Voters (U.S.); Egg decoration; Folk art -- United States; Political campaigns -- United States; Urban renewal -- Illinois -- Chicago; Visual aids; Visual communication; Women in politics -- United States; Hyde Park (Chicago, Ill.); Kenwood (Chicago, Ill.); Woodlawn (Chicago, Ill.); Speechwriters
INVENTORY
- Series I: Early Writing
  Series I contains much of Goetz’s early work on the use of new media by state and local governments. Included here are her two presentation binders on the use of visual aids, "Untapped Potential" and "Visual Aids and State Governments," as well as her book, Visual Aids for the Public Service, published in English and in a Vietnamese translation. Materials relating to Goetz’s 1954-1955 University of Chicago course on public television, Communications 311, The Communication of Ideas by Television, are also contained here. Additionally, Series I holds photocopies of book reviews written by Goetz for the United States Information Agency between 1959 and 1976. A box of slides relating to "Visual Aids and State Governments" is housed in Series VI.
  - American Public Works Administration, Films in Public Works, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 1-2)
  - Communications 311, syllabus and auxiliary materials, 1954-1955 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Communications 311, syllabus, correspondence, and clippings, 1954-1955 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Draft application on behalf of a public service audio-visual center, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Evidence of need for a public affairs communication center, 1951-1952 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - The Language of Visual Communication, summaries and outlines, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Public Administration Clearing House, drafts, correspondence, 1951-1954 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Public Administration Clearing House, drafts, correspondence, 1951-1954 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Public Administration Clearing House, 1952-1954 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Report on the availability of bank credit in the seventh federal reserve district, book and newspaper clipping, 1934-1935 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - "Short Cuts to Leadership for the Atomic Age," Adult Education Bulletin, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Sixty Years of 16mm Film, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - United States Information Agency, book reviews, 1959-1976 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - "Untapped Potential" visual aid presentation binder, front matter, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - "Untapped Potential" visual aid presentation binder, in federal government, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - "Untapped Potential" visual aid presentation binder, in state and local government, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - "Untapped Potential" visual aid presentation binder, in international government, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - "Untapped Potential" visual aid presentation binder, in industry and education, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - "Visual Aids and State Governments" presentation binder, general information, 1951-1953 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - "Visual Aids and State Governments" presentation binder, film utilization, 1951-1953 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - "Visual Aids and State Governments" presentation binder, graphics and displays, 1951-1953 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - "Visual Aids and State Governments" presentation binder, sample communications, 1951-1953 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - "Visual Aids and State Governments," State Government magazine, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Visual Aids for the Public Service, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Visual Aids for the Public Service, Vietnamese translation, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - WTTW, correspondence, script, letter to the editor, 1954-1990 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Series II: National Political Activities
  Series II houses materials relating to Goetz’s work in national politics in the 1950s. The majority of the series contains documents from Adlai Stevenson’s 1956 presidential campaign, including drafts of speeches, memoranda, position papers, and correspondence. Additionally, the series holds drafts, correspondence, and a final manuscript of the 1958 book Goetz co-authored with Chicago politician Robert Merriam, Going Into Politics.
  - Adlai Stevenson, photographs, 1956-1966 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Campaign speeches, drafts, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Campaign speeches, drafts, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, Goetz to Stevenson, 1952-1958 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, Stevenson to Goetz, 1952-1962 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, Stevenson campaign, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence and outlines, 1952-1959 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence and photographs, photocopies, 1954-1957 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Letterhead, Stevenson-Kefauver campaign committee, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Memoranda, California campaign trip, 1956 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Memoranda, Florida campaign trip, 1956 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Memoranda, Oregon campaign trip, 1956 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Memoranda, Stevenson campaign, 1956 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Merriam and Goetz, correspondence and clippings, 1956-1958 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Merriam and Goetz manuscript, editorial comments, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Merriam and Merriam book on international political cooperation, Goetz outlines and drafts, 1949-1951 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Nomination acceptance speech, 1956 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Notes, women’s vote, 1956 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Philadelphia campaign visit, local arrangements, 1956 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Program for children, Parents magazine, 1956 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Souvenirs, 1956 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Szilard, Leo, article, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Women’s vote, position paper, 1956 (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Series III: Local Activism
  Series III contains papers relating to Goetz’s work on the Hyde Park-Kenwood urban renewal project of the 1950s and 1960s and her general research and writing on urban renewal in the wake of Hyde Park’s success. Included here are Goetz’s subject folders on the Hyde Park-Kenwood project, holding newspapers clippings, correspondence, and meeting minutes. The series also contains drafts and manuscripts of her three books on urban renewal, The Hidden Price of Urban Renewal, Middle-Income Housing, and her significant revision of Peter Rossi and Robert Dentler’s The Politics of Urban Renewal. An oversized map of the Hyde Park-Kenwood Urban Renewal Project is also held in Series VI.
  - American Council to Improve our Neighborhoods, Hyde Park-Kenwood community council conference pamphlet, 1956 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Chicago League of Women Voters, 1940-1944 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Chicago Department of Urban Renewal, Hyde Park service center, clippings, 1963 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - "Community Initiative in Renewal - The Chicago Story," outlines, 1961-1962 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - "Citizens in Urban Renewal," Sears Roebuck pamphlet, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, Chicago’s American articles, 1961-1962 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, D. E. Mackelmann, Department of Urban Renewal, with partial draft of Rachel Goetz’s rewrite of Peter H. Rossi and Robert A. Dentler’s The Politics of Urban Renewal, 1961-1962 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Middle-Income Housing, correspondence, 1959-1961 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Urban renewal, correspondence, 1957-1963 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Department of Urban Renewal, draft of book chapter on South East Chicago Commission and role of university, 1962 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - 53rd Street and Kimbark Avenue shopping center, correspondence, drafts, and articles, 1963 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - "Ghosts of 1025 Connecticut Avenue," notes and drafts, 1966 and n.d. (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - The Hidden Price of Urban Renewal, draft and outlines, 1961 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - The Hidden Price of Urban Renewal, final manuscript, front matter, 1963 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - The Hidden Price of Urban Renewal, final manuscript, chapter I, 1963 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - The Hidden Price of Urban Renewal, final manuscript, chapter II, 1963 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - The Hidden Price of Urban Renewal, final manuscript, chapter III, 1963 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - The Hidden Price of Urban Renewal, final manuscript, chapter IV, 1963 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - The Hidden Price of Urban Renewal, final manuscript, chapter V, 1963 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - The Hidden Price of Urban Renewal, final manuscript, chapter VI, 1963 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - The Hidden Price of Urban Renewal, final manuscript, chapter VII, 1963 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - The Hidden Price of Urban Renewal, final manuscript, chapter VIII, 1963 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - The Hidden Price of Urban Renewal, final manuscript, chapter IX, 1963 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - The Hidden Price of Urban Renewal, final manuscript, chapter X, 1963 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - The Hidden Price of Urban Renewal, complete copy, 1963 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Hyde Park-Kenwood Community Conference, correspondence, clippings, newsletters, 1956-1963 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Hyde Park-Kenwood Community Conference, planning committee, meeting minutes, 1958-1960 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Hyde Park-Kenwood urban renewal project, A and B sites, clippings, 1958-1961 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Hyde Park-Kenwood urban renewal project, citizen attitudes, clippings, 1958 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Hyde Park-Kenwood urban renewal project, city council hearings, minutes and clippings, 1958 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Hyde Park-Kenwood urban renewal project, enforcement, notes and clippings, 1960-1962 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Hyde Park-Kenwood urban renewal project, financing, notes and clippings, 1951-1961 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Hyde Park-Kenwood urban renewal project, general, notes and clippings, 1957-1962 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Hyde Park-Kenwood urban renewal project, general, notes and clippings, 1957-1962 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Hyde Park-Kenwood urban renewal project, general, notes and clippings, 1957-1962 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Hyde Park-Kenwood urban renewal project, photocopied Chicago’s American clippings, 1962-1963 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Hyde Park-Kenwood urban renewal project, photographs, 1950-1951 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Hyde Park-Kenwood urban renewal project, promotional materials, 1961-1965 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Hyde Park-Kenwood urban renewal project, public housing, notes and clippings, 1958-1960 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Hyde Park-Kenwood urban renewal project, rehabilitation, clippings, 1960-1961 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Hyde Park-Kenwood urban renewal project, relocation, clippings, 1957-1960 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Hyde Park-Kenwood urban renewal project, roadblocks, notes and clippings, 1958-1960 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Hyde Park-Kenwood urban renewal project, writings by Perloff and Tax, 1955-1958 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Hyde Park-Kenwood urban renewal project, zoning, notes and clippings, 1957-1959 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Hyde Park Neighborhood Club, building fund and dedication of new home, 1950-1951 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Middle-Income Housing, outlines and proposals, 1959-1961 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Middle-Income Housing, front matter, 1962 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Middle-Income Housing, chapter I, 1962 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Middle-Income Housing, chapter II, 1962 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Middle-Income Housing, chapter III, 1962 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Middle-Income Housing, chapter IV, 1962 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Middle-Income Housing, chapter V, 1962 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Middle-Income Housing, chapter VI, 1962 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Middle-Income Housing, chapter VII, 1962 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Middle-Income Housing, chapter VIII, early draft, 1960 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Middle-Income Housing, Chicago story, manuscript and correspondence, 1961 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Middle-Income Housing, complete copy, 1962 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Progressive Grocer magazine, article and correspondence, 1963-1964 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Proposal for a program to meet the long-term needs of Woodlawn, 1962 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - "Public Policy and Private Profits - The National Housing Dilemma," correspondence, drafts, article, 1963-1964 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Reactions to Chicago’s American series on urban renewal, 1961-1962 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Renewing Chicago in the ‘60s, lecture and discussion series, 1961 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Rossi and Dentler, The Politics of Urban Renewal, Goetz rewrite, revised Chicago chapter, notes, clippings, 1960 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Rossi and Dentler, The Politics of Urban Renewal, Goetz rewrite, permissions and preface by D.E. Mackelmann, 1962-1987 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Rossi and Dentler, The Politics of Urban Renewal, Goetz rewrite, chapter I, 1962 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Rossi and Dentler, The Politics of Urban Renewal, Goetz rewrite, chapter II, 1962 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Rossi and Dentler, The Politics of Urban Renewal, Goetz rewrite, chapter III, 1962 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Rossi and Dentler, The Politics of Urban Renewal, Goetz rewrite, chapter IV, 1962 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Rossi and Dentler, The Politics of Urban Renewal, Goetz rewrite, chapter V, 1962, Series III: Local Activism (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Rossi and Dentler, The Politics of Urban Renewal, Goetz rewrite, chapter VI, 1962 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Rossi and Dentler, The Politics of Urban Renewal, Goetz rewrite, chapter VII, 1962 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Rossi and Dentler, The Politics of Urban Renewal, Goetz rewrite, chapter VIII, 1962 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Rossi and Dentler, The Politics of Urban Renewal, Goetz rewrite, chapter IX, 1962 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Rossi and Dentler, The Politics of Urban Renewal, Goetz rewrite, chapter X, 1962 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Rossi and Dentler, The Politics of Urban Renewal, Goetz rewrite, chapter XI, 1962 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Rossi and Dentler, The Politics of Urban Renewal, Goetz rewrite, part I, 1962 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Rossi and Dentler, The Politics of Urban Renewal, Goetz rewrite, part II, 1962 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Slum prevention book, outlines, 1962-1963 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - "The Social Power Position of a Real Estate Board," Donald Bouma paper, 1961 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - South East Chicago Commission, notes, minutes, clippings, 1958-1959 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - South East Chicago Commission, notes, minutes, clippings, 1960-1962 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - South East Chicago Commission and Hyde Park-Kenwood Community Conference, plans for urban renewal, 1952-1959 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Southwest Hyde Park Neighborhood Association, clippings, notes, reports, 1957-1958 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Tax incentives, notes, 1959 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Taxes and growth of slums, notes and clippings, 1957-1961 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - University of Chicago, housing segregation, clippings, 1962-1963 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - University of Chicago, south campus, clippings, 1960-1961 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Urban renewal, articles, 1959-1964 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Urban renewal, Chicago’s American articles, 1961-1963 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Urban renewal, pamphlets and reports, 1958-1964 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Woodlawn renewal, industrial areas foundation chapter, draft, notes, clippings, 1963 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Woodlawn renewal, general, clippings and notes, 1961-1963 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Woodlawn renewal, temporary Woodlawn organization chapter, draft, notes, clippings, 1961-1963 (Box 11, Folder 11)
- Series IV: Personal Material
  Series IV holds personal information on Goetz and her family. A significant portion of the series relates to Goetz’s egg art, a project to which she dedicated herself from the mid-1970s until her death in 1994. Newspaper clippings, correspondence, and many photographs of her decorated eggs are included here. The series also holds a small amount of Goetz’s work with Midway Editorial Research, a Chicago-based research firm which she co-founded in the mid-1960s. Additionally, materials relating to Goetz’s father, Leon Carroll Marshall, are housed in this series. These documents include newspaper clippings, photographs, and correspondence regarding Marshall’s life and Goetz’s work to establish a University of Chicago business school scholarship in his name.
  - Academic record and résumé, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Articles, freelance, drafts, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Articles and essays, 1934-1960 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Curriculum vita, 1953-1958 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Decorated eggs, correspondence, clippings, 1976-1994 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Decorated eggs, correspondence, articles, newsletters, 1978-1994 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Decorated eggs, photographs, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Decorated eggs, photographs, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Decorated eggs, photographs, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Decorated eggs, photographs, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Essays, 1961 and n.d. (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Goetz, Roger, birth certificate, school record, father’s obituary, 1906-1935 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Hyde Park Book Club, 1949-1972 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Keen, S.A., Faith Papers, annotated, 1898 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Marshall, Leon C., clippings, correspondence, obituaries, 1934-1966 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Marshall, Leon C., 80th birthday, correspondence, essay by Billy Goetz, 1959 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Marshall, Leon C., photographs, 1934-1935 and n.d. (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Marshall, Leon C. papers, University of Wyoming finding aid, correspondence, 1966-1995 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Marshall, Leon C., remembrances, biographical material, correspondence, obituaries, 1966-1995 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Marshall, Leon C., scholarship fund, correspondence, 1983-1987 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Marshall, Leon C., writings, 1899-1948 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Marshall, Leon C. Jr., the battlefields of France, book I, scrapbook, 1925 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Marshall, Leon C. Jr., the battlefields of France, book II, scrapbook, 1925 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Marshall, Leon C. Jr., Phi Kappa Psi songbook, 1928 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Midway editorial research, Chicago Sun-Times article, 1966 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Midway Editorial Research, "Challenge and Response," Jewish Children’s Bureau pamphlet, 1965 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Midway Editorial Research, Jewish Children’s Bureau pamphlet, 1970 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Midway Editorial Research, Minority Employment Patterns in an Urban Labor Market - The Chicago Experience, 1967 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - "Outsmart the Holdup Man," personal safety article and correspondence, 1959 (Box 15, Folder 4-5)
  - Vital information, academic record, obituaries, 1961-1994 (Box 15, Folder 6)
- Series V: Audio Material